Edward Mann

Software Developer

Since leaving University I have had the opportunity to work for a small web development agency, complete Freelance assignments and currently a London-based online startup. During this time I have developed and released applications in OO-PHP (Laravel and Symfony 2), Python and Java.

Contact

Web: eddmann.com

Email: the@eddmann.com

Mobile: 07517 335305

In one such startup I was tasked with both the development and accompanying load-distribution of a three server LAMP setup. This included a web application written in CodeIgniter, internal maintenance/data crawlers written in Python/Shell and a mobile application written in JavaScript (Titanium SDK). The mobile application has since been successfully released into the iTunes and Android stores.

A large Freelance project I also undertook was to begin implementing the fundamental feature-set for a Resource Management System written in Laravel and Sphinx. This has since been successfully passed over to another developer, thanks to strong use of Git, Composer, Vagrant and PHPUnit (with valuable tests).

Within my current role at MyBuilder I am tasked with maintaining and improving on the core product. This entails working with other developers, liaising with internal domain experts, and creating features using Symfony 2 and Swift (iOS) that meet their needs. Throughout this time I have been fortunate to gain successful experience working in Domain-Driven Developed and TDD projects.

I enjoy the practical application of software design and development, however, I still feel the need and find significant enjoyment in continuing to learn in this ever-changing field. As a result of this, I spend many hours outside of work blogging about my latest technical interests and share a weekly podcast with a group of like-minded developers. At present I am also reviewing Domain-Driven Design in PHP, a Leanpub book cowritten by a work colleague.

Skills

- Java
- PHP
- Python
- JavaScript

- Swift (iOS)
- Scala
- ullet Unit Testing/TDD ullet Git

- DDD
- Unix
- Symfony 2
- PostgreSQL

Interests

- Writing online about new languages and technologies
- Weekly development podcast (Three Devs and a Maybe) with a group of previous work-colleagues
- Photography
- Basketball

Work Experience

MyBuilder Limited

Software Engineer, 2014 - Present

- o PHP based Symfony 2 Web application
- o Use of Git, Jenkins, PHPUnit, PostgreSQL
- o Experience using DDD and TDD in production

Freelance Software Developer, 2013

- Long-term Laravel 4 project with Sphinx
- o Use of Git, Vagrant, Composer and PHPUnit
- Management of the full-stack, CentOS/Nginx/PHP/MySQL

360 Software Solutions

Web Developer, 2011 - 2013

- o Developed a modular MVC PHP content-management platform
- o Lead development on a large web-based mobile search engine startup
- o Created and shipped an iOS/Android mobile application using Titanium

Education

BSc Internet Computing

First Class Honours, 2008 - 2011

University of Greenwich

London, England

BTEC National Diploma for IT Practitioners

Distinction, Distinction, Merit

West Kent College

Tonbridge, Kent

Secondary School GCSEs

14 Gained A* - C (Maths, English & Science inc.)

Hugh Christie Technology College

Tonbridge, Kent

References

Available upon request.